

## Summary

I've been writing code since I was 13, and professionally for the past decade. My specialty is writing *fast* and *clean* code, and my favorite language is **Rust**.

I'm currently employed as a *Quantitative Portfolio Manager*. I write trading algorithms and quantitative analysis tools to help making investment decisions. I use **Python**, its data science stack (**pandas**, **numpy**, **jupyter**) and native extensions for exploratory analyses, and **Rust** for time-sensitive and mission-critical applications. I tend to architect my applications in *microservices* and deploy using **Docker** where appropriate.

I want to build software that makes a net positive difference in the world. I want my efforts to be meaningful and make people's lives easier and happier, and won't accept jobs which are exploitative of others or unethical in nature.

## **Employment History**

### Azimut Capital Management sgr

10/2017 - present day

- Developed a portfolio and order management system for fast automated strategy signal computation, portfolio differencing and order generation. Written in Rust, sourcing prices data from IQFeed / Bloomberg API, deployed in the context of time-sensitive equity strategies (operations on tens of single-stocks for tens of client accounts as close to the end of trading day as possible).
- Developed a proprietary backtesting platform in the form of a C++ CPython extension, supporting Jupyter widgets via Vue.js/Web Components. Mixed vector/event-driven architecture, allowing limit orders, margin trading, portfolio weight targeting, integrating with the Pandas/NumPy/SciPy stack.
- Implemented an automated signal generation pipeline for the AZ MA Algo Equity Strategies fund: relative vol trading of VIX ETNs replicated via futures, long-short momentum and mean reversion on index futures, with parametric diversification.

## Interfase s.r.l. 08/2012 - 02/2018

- Developed a multi-monitor interactive data visualization installation, controlled from a terminal with a local ad-hoc network
- Developed a distributed multi-device Virtual Reality immersive video player, with playback controlled by a narrator with a remote application
- Developed a GIS tool for visually designing domain-specific scenarios, feeding the result to a mathematical model engine and reporting upon its output

GWC World 08/2011 - 06/2013

Standouter.com *08/2011 - 08/2012* 

#### Skills

#### Software Development

Rust  $\cdot$  C++11  $\cdot$  Python  $\cdot$  Javascript  $\cdot$  Functional programming  $\cdot$  Low-level performance optimization  $\cdot$  Concurrency  $\cdot$  Parallelism

#### **Ouant Finance & Data Science**

Pandas · NumPy · Jupyter Notebooks · SQL · Algorithmic trading · Econometrics · Equities · Futures · Derivatives

#### Frontend

Javascript/ES6 · Interactive data visualization · WebGL · Canvas2D · Vue.js · Svelte.js

#### Backend & DevOps

RESTful API · Microservices · Docker · Docker Compose · Node.js · Java EE

## **Graphics Programming**

Real-time rendering · Computational geometry · Shading algorithms · Procedural content generation

## Machine Learning

Neural networks · Deep learning · Computer vision (OpenCV) · Linear/nonlinear programming · Regression analysis

## Education

# MSc Finance & Risk Management

110L/110 2018

Università degli Studi di Firenze

Thesis: "Deep Learning models for High-Frequency Cryptocurrency Forecasting". I applied a long short-term memory based recurrent deep neural network to intraday pricing data for a number of cryptocurrencies listed on the GDAX exchange. Findings showed that a simple model on 5-minute data is unable to forecast returns, but may forecast realized volatility (squared returns) with significant precision.

# BSc Computer Science

103/110 *2015* 

Università degli Studi di Firenze

Thesis: "Procedural Content Generation and Real-time Rendering". I researched and designed a mathematical formalism by merging parametric open L-systems and shape grammars to define urban architectural elements and procedurally generate 3D models of cities. The models were textured with signal function-based, anti-aliased procedural textures and rendered in the context of a deferred, multi-pass shading renderer.

## Diploma di Perito Informatico

100/100 *2008* 

I.T.I.S. "T. Buzzi"

.S. "I. Buzzi"